<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>YAL/TB</title>
    <link>https://apinter.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on YAL/TB</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>GNU FDL 1.3</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 03 Feb 2021 10:16:19 +0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://apinter.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Syncing a fork with upstream</title>
      <link>https://apinter.github.io/posts/git-sync-upstream-fork/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Feb 2021 10:16:19 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://apinter.github.io/posts/git-sync-upstream-fork/</guid>
      <description>Getting started By now you&amp;rsquo;re probably familiar with git. Git is a popular distributed version control system with which people can collaborate on pretty much anything that you can/want to version control and collaborate on. This can be source code, documentation, automation scripts, anything really. To work on a project with others, one would generally create a fork of the main repository where the code, it&amp;rsquo;s branches and issues are being stored at.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Initial Commit</title>
      <link>https://apinter.github.io/posts/initial-commit/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Jan 2021 19:33:46 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://apinter.github.io/posts/initial-commit/</guid>
      <description>Purpose First of all this a GNU/Linux - and mostly openSUSE - focused technical blog with a bunch of know-how, tools, personal recommendations. Recently had this realization that the content I&amp;rsquo;m keeping in my QOwnNotes would be a little bit more valuable if&amp;hellip;
 ..it would be available publicly, ..it would be DDG/Google searchable, ..I could just link to it when I&amp;rsquo;m helping others AkA &amp;ldquo;laziness&amp;rdquo;.  Being active in different communities, I run into a lot of repeated questions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://apinter.github.io/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://apinter.github.io/about/</guid>
      <description>whoami My name is Attila Pinter. I&amp;rsquo;ve been into computers since I was 6 years old. I got deep into Linux when I was 14, fast forward to today and Linux is what I make a living with. Been studying IT in my younger years, but schools were not as great at teaching or knowledge transfer as the community is. I did spent a month at university - which I got into with full scholarship -, but considered it a waste of my time and bailed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://apinter.github.io/archives/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://apinter.github.io/archives/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
